Over the past 10 years,
过去的十年，
I've been researching the way people organize and visualize information.
我一直在研究，人们如何整理和构想信息
And I've noticed an interesting shift.
期间我发现了一个有趣的变化。
For a long period of time,
很长一段时间里，
we believed in a natural ranking order in the world around us,
我们相信我们所置身的这个世界的自然秩序，
also known as the great chain of being, or "Scala naturae" in Latin,
也称作“生存巨链”，或拉丁文里的“自然级别”
a top-down structure that normally starts with God at the very top,
一般以神为顶点而开端自上而下
followed by angels, noblemen,
下面是天使、贵族、
common people, animals, and so on.
平民、动物等。
This idea was actually based on Aristotle's ontology,
这理念其实是基于亚里士多德的本体论，
which classified all things known to man in a set of opposing categories,
它将人类所知的东西按对立关系分类，
like the ones you see behind me.
比如我身后这个例子。
But over time, interestingly enough,
但随着时间的推移，有趣的是
this concept adopted the branching schema of a tree
这个理念吸收了来自树的分支结构，
in what became known as the Porphyrian tree,
后被称为“波菲利之树”，
also considered to be the oldest tree of knowledge.
这也被认为是最早的智慧之树。
The branching scheme of the tree was, in fact,
实际上，树的分支结构
such a powerful metaphor for conveying information
可以有效而形象地传递信息。
that it became, over time, an important communication tool
它逐渐变成了一个重要的交流工具，
to map a variety of systems of knowledge.
用以描绘不同的知识系统。
We can see trees being used to map morality,
我们可以发现树曾被用来描绘道德。
with the popular tree of virtues and tree of vices,
如人们熟知的善与恶之树。
as you can see here, with these beautiful illustrations from medieval Europe.
比如这些来自欧洲中世纪的美丽插图。
We can see trees being used to map consanguinity,
树也被用以描述血缘关系。
the various blood ties between people.
人们之间各种血缘关系。
We can also see trees being used to map genealogy,
树也被用来描述家族谱系，
perhaps the most famous archetype of the tree diagram.
这可能是最著名而原始的树形图表。
I think many of you in the audience have probably seen family trees.
我想在座很多听众都见过树形族谱。
Many of you probably even have your own family trees drawn in such a way.
你们之中的很多人的族谱可能和这些图类似。
We can see trees even mapping systems of law,
树也被用来描绘法律系统，
the various decrees and rulings of kings and rulers.
各种国王和掌权者的法令和规定。
And finally, of course, also a very popular scientific metaphor,
最后，当然它通常还是科学的象征。
we can see trees being used to map all species known to man.
如图，树被用来归纳人类已知物种。
And trees ultimately became such a powerful visual metaphor
最终，树变为一种有效的视觉象征。
because in many ways, they really embody this human desire
因为它在很多方面都能体现，
for order, for balance, for unity, for symmetry.
人类对秩序、平衡、统一、对称的渴望。
However, nowadays we are really facing new complex, intricate challenges
但如今，我们正面临错中复杂的新难题，
that cannot be understood by simply employing a simple tree diagram.
它们难以用简单的树形来描绘。
And a new metaphor is currently emerging,
一种新的视觉隐喻在逐渐成型，
and it's currently replacing the tree
它在逐渐取代树。
in visualizing various systems of knowledge.
在各种图形化的知识系统中，
It's really providing us with a new lens to understand the world around us.
它为我们对世界的认识提供了新视角。
And this new metaphor is the metaphor of the network.
这种新形象就是网络结构。
And we can see this shift from trees into networks
我们可以发现网络逐渐取代树，
in many domains of knowledge.
出现在各知识领域。
We can see this shift in the way we try to understand the brain.
这种转变也发生在我们对大脑的认识。
While before, we used to think of the brain as a modular, centralized organ,
过去我们把大脑看作一个分块的中枢器官，
where a given area was responsible for a set of actions and behaviors,
特定的区域控制特定的反应和行为。
the more we know about the brain,
当我们对大脑了解越多，
the more we think of it as a large music symphony,
就越觉得它像一部大型交响乐，
played by hundreds and thousands of instruments.
由数以千计的乐器演奏出来。
This is a beautiful snapshot created by the Blue Brain Project,
这幅美妙的快照来自于蓝脑计划，
where you can see 10,000 neurons and 30 million connections.
里面有一万个神经元和三千万条连接。
And this is only mapping 10 percent of a mammalian neocortex.
这仅表现了哺乳类的新大脑皮质的10%。
We can also see this shift in the way we try to conceive of human knowledge.
这种转变也体现在我们对人类知识的构想。
These are some remarkable trees of knowledge, or trees of science,
这是些很出色的知识树或科学树，
by Spanish scholar Ramon Llull.
出自西班牙学者Ramon Llull。
And Llull was actually the precursor,
Llull是一个先驱，
the very first one who created the metaphor of science as a tree,
是首个用树形结构来表现科学的人。
a metaphor we use every single day, when we say,
一个我们每天都用到的形象，例如：
"Biology is a branch of science,"
“生物学是科学的分支。”
when we say,
当我们说：
"Genetics is a branch of science."
“遗传学是科学的分支。”
But perhaps the most beautiful of all trees of knowledge, at least for me,
于我而言，最美的知识树可能是，
was created for the French encyclopedia by Diderot and d'Alembert in 1751.
Diderot和d'Alembert在1751年为法国大百科全书创作的。
This was really the bastion of the French Enlightenment,
它体现了法国启蒙运动的成就，
and this gorgeous illustration was featured as a table of contents for the encyclopedia.
这幅美妙的图表成为了最具特色的目录出现在百科全书上。
And it actually maps out all domains of knowledge
事实上它将各领域的知识，
as separate branches of a tree.
划分于树的各个分支上。
But knowledge is much more intricate than this.
但知识是更错综复杂的。
These are two maps of Wikipedia showing the inter-linkage of articles --
这两幅来自维基的图，表现了文章间的关联，
related to history on the left, and mathematics on the right.
与左边的历史和右边的数学有关联。
And I think by looking at these maps
我认为，这两幅图
and other ones that have been created of Wikipedia --
以及维基百科上的其他图，
arguably one of the largest rhizomatic structures ever created by man --
可以说是人类创造的最庞大的根茎结构。
we can really understand how human knowledge is much more intricate
由此可看出，人类知识是如此错综复杂、
and interdependent, just like a network.
相互关联，就像一个网络。
We can also see this interesting shift
这种有趣的转变，
in the way we map social ties between people.
也体现在我们描绘人们的社会关系中。
This is the typical organization chart.
这是张典型的组织机构图。
I'm assuming many of you have seen a similar chart as well,
我相信在座很多听众也见过类似的，
in your own corporations, or others.
在你们的公司或其他机构中。
It's a top-down structure
这是个至上而下结构，
that normally starts with the CEO at the very top,
一般是CEO在顶端，
and where you can drill down all the way to the individual workmen on the bottom.
往下一直延伸到底部的各工作人员。
But humans sometimes are, well, actually, all humans are unique in their own way,
但每个人都有自己的独特之处。
and sometimes you really don't play well under this really rigid structure.
但有时你无法在这种僵硬的框架下施展所有才能。
I think the Internet is really changing this paradigm quite a lot.
网络大幅度改变了这一架构。
This is a fantastic map of online social collaboration
这张奇妙的图形展示了网络上
between Perl developers.
Perl 开发者间的社群合作。
Perl is a famous programming language,
Perl 是种著名的编程语言，
and here, you can see how different programmers
在此，你可以看到那些不同的程序员
are actually exchanging files, and working together on a given project.
在为定制的项目交换文件和协同工作。
And here, you can notice that this is a completely decentralized process --
你可以发现，这个开发过程是完全分散的。
there's no leader in this organization,
这个组织里没有领导人，
it's a network.
这是个网络。
We can also see this interesting shift when we look at terrorism.
这种有趣的转变，也出现在恐怖主义者中。
One of the main challenges of understanding terrorism nowadays
当今研究恐怖主义最主要的挑战是
is that we are dealing with decentralized, independent cells,
我们正在和一个权力分散、个体独立，
where there's no leader leading the whole process.
没有领导人统筹整个过程的组织打交道。
And here, you can actually see how visualization is being used.
这里，你看到了信息的视觉化的应用。
The diagram that you see behind me
我身后这个图，
shows all the terrorists involved in the Madrid attack in 2004.
展示了参与2004年马德里袭击的恐怖分子。
And what they did here is, they actually segmented the network
这张图展示了他们所做的，
into three different years,
事实上他们将整个过程按年份分为三段，
represented by the vertical layers that you see behind me.
如我身后所展示的这三个垂直平面。
And the blue lines tie together
将平面联系起来的蓝线，
the people that were present in that network year after year.
代表了每年都参与了的人。
So even though there's no leader per se,
因此，虽然没有领导人，
these people are probably the most influential ones in that organization,
这些人可能是组织中最具影响力的。
the ones that know more about the past,
他们是这个特殊结构中最了解计划的过去
and the future plans and goals of this particular cell.
未来以及最终目的人。
We can also see this shift from trees into networks
这种从树到网络的转变，
in the way we classify and organize species.
也出现在我们对物种的分类。
The image on the right is the only illustration
右边这幅图，
that Darwin included in "The Origin of Species,"
是达尔文的《物种起源》中唯一的图。
which Darwin called the "Tree of Life."
达尔文称之为“生命之树”。
There's actually a letter from Darwin to the publisher,
这实际是他给出版社的信，
expanding on the importance of this particular diagram.
用以解释这种结构的重要性。
It was critical for Darwin's theory of evolution.
对于达尔文进化论，这很重要。
But recently, scientists discovered that overlaying this tree of life
但科学家最近发现在这生命之树下，
is a dense network of bacteria,
是个密集的细菌网络。
and these bacteria are actually tying together
而正是这些细菌
species that were completely separated before,
将那些原本无关的物种联系起来，
to what scientists are now calling not the tree of life,
科学家不再称之为生命之树，
but the web of life, the network of life.
而称为生命之网，一张连接生命的网络。
And finally, we can really see this shift, again,
最后一个例子，这种转变
when we look at ecosystems around our planet.
也体现于地球生态系统中。
No more do we have these simplified predator-versus-prey diagrams
不再是这简化的捕食与被捕食，
we have all learned at school.
如在校学到的那样。
This is a much more accurate depiction of an ecosystem.
这图更准确地描绘了生态系统。
This is a diagram created by Professor David Lavigne,
这个图出自David Lavigne教授。
mapping close to 100 species that interact with the codfish
描绘了与鳕鱼相关的近100种物种，
off the coast of Newfoundland in Canada.
位于加拿大纽芬兰沿岸。
And I think here, we can really understand the intricate and interdependent nature
由此，可以明白地球各生态系统中，
of most ecosystems that abound on our planet.
错综复杂、相互依存的本质。
But even though recent, this metaphor of the network,
而如今，这种网络状的形象
is really already adopting various shapes and forms,
已经有不同的形状和形式，
and it's almost becoming a growing visual taxonomy.
变成一门逐渐壮大的视觉分类学，
It's almost becoming the syntax of a new language.
几乎成为一门新语言的语法。
And this is one aspect that truly fascinates me.
这一点非常吸引我。
And these are actually 15 different typologies
实际上，有15种类型学，
I've been collecting over time,
是我逐渐收集到的，
and it really shows the immense visual diversity of this new metaphor.
图中显示了这新形象极具多样性。
And here is an example.
举例而言，
On the very top band, you have radial convergence,
最上排是径向会聚型。
a visualization model that has become really popular over the last five years.
过去5年中，这个视觉模型广受欢迎。
At the top left, the very first project is a gene network,
左上角，它最初是个基因网络，
followed by a network of IP addresses -- machines, servers --
紧接着是IP地址、机器、服务器、
followed by a network of Facebook friends.
以及脸书网友的网络。
You probably couldn't find more disparate topics,
可能你难以找到与此迥异的话题，
yet they are using the same metaphor, the same visual model,
但它们都用着相同的形象与视觉模型，
to map the never-ending complexities of its own subject.
用以表现这一主题其自身永无止境的复杂性。
And here are a few more examples of the many I've been collecting,
再举些我收集到的例子，
of this growing visual taxonomy of networks.
它们运用了这种视觉分类网络。
But networks are not just a scientific metaphor.
但网络不仅仅有科学化的形象。
As designers, researchers, and scientists try to map a variety of complex systems,
当设计师、研究员、科学家尽力地表达各种复杂系统，
they are in many ways influencing traditional art fields,
它们正以不同方式影响着传统艺术领域，
like painting and sculpture,
如绘画和雕塑，
and influencing many different artists.
同样影响着不同的艺术家们。
And perhaps because networks have this huge aesthetical force to them --
或许网络对他们有着巨大的美学推动力，
they're immensely gorgeous --
它们如此多彩绚烂，
they are really becoming a cultural meme,
以致成为一种文化因子，
and driving a new art movement, which I've called "networkism."
促成了一种新艺术运动，我称之为“网络主义”。
And we can see this influence in this movement in a variety of ways.
它从多个方面影响着这场艺术运动。
This is just one of many examples,
这是其中一个例子，
where you can see this influence from science into art.
表明这种影响从科学延伸到艺术。
The example on your left side is IP-mapping,
左边的是IP映射，一幅电脑生成的映射图，
a computer-generated map of IP addresses; again -- servers, machines.
及服务器、机器的网络。
And on your right side,
在右边的是，
you have "Transient Structures and Unstable Networks" by Sharon Molloy,
Sharon Molloy的《瞬时结构与非稳定网络》，
using oil and enamel on canvas.
用油彩与珐琅绘于帆布上。
And here are a few more paintings by Sharon Molloy,
这些作品也来自于Sharon Molloy，
some gorgeous, intricate paintings.
是些美妙、繁复的画作。
And here's another example of that interesting cross-pollination
这是另一个例子，关于科学与艺术之间
between science and art.
异花授粉式的交融和影响。
On your left side, you have "Operation Smile."
左边的是《微笑行动》，
It is a computer-generated map of a social network.
是幅电脑生成的社交网络图。
And on your right side, you have "Field 4," by Emma McNally,
在右边的是出自Emma McNally的《字段4》，
using only graphite on paper.
仅用石墨绘于纸上。
Emma McNally is one of the main leaders of this movement,
Emma McNally是这场艺术运动中的主要领袖之一，
and she creates these striking, imaginary landscapes,
她创造了这些惊艳而富想象力的作品，
where you can really notice the influence from traditional network visualization.
由此可见传统网络视觉化对其的影响。
But networkism doesn't happen only in two dimensions.
但网络主义不仅限于二维平面。
This is perhaps one of my favorite projects of this new movement.
这可能是这场新运动中我最喜欢的作品之一。
And I think the title really says it all -- it's called:
我认为它的名字很好的描述了它，
"Galaxies Forming Along Filaments,
“陷落在丝状中的星系，
Like Droplets Along the Strands of a Spider's Web."
犹如蜘蛛网上的悬挂的水珠。”
And I just find this particular project to be immensely powerful.
我觉得这个作品非常震撼，
It was created by Tomás Saraceno,
它是Tomás Saraceno的作品。
and he occupies these large spaces,
他在这种大空间中，
creates these massive installations using only elastic ropes.
仅用弹性绳来编织这巨大的装置。
As you actually navigate that space and bounce along those elastic ropes,
当你在其中穿梭，碰到这些弹性绳，
the entire network kind of shifts, almost like a real organic network would.
整个网会变形，就像个活生生的有机网络。
And here's yet another example
这是另一个例子，
of networkism taken to a whole different level.
网络主义被发挥至一个全新的水平。
This was created by Japanese artist Chiharu Shiota
它是日本艺术家塩田千春的作品，
in a piece called "In Silence."
名为《寂静》。
And Chiharu, like Tomás Saraceno, fills these rooms with this dense network,
如同Tomás Saraceno的作品，她让这些空间布满网络，
this dense web of elastic ropes and black wool and thread,
由弹性绳、黑毛线、棉线编织的巨网。
sometimes including objects, as you can see here,
有时加入了一些物品，
sometimes even including people, in many of her installations.
在她的一些作品中有时还有人。
But networks are also not just a new trend,
但网络不仅仅是种趋势，
and it's too easy for us to dismiss it as such.
我们容易认为它的影响仅此而已。
Networks really embody notions of decentralization,
网络很好地表现了
of interconnectedness, of interdependence.
零散、关联、以及互相依存这些概念。
And this new way of thinking is critical
这种新思维非常对我们来说很重要，
for us to solve many of the complex problems we are facing nowadays,
可用以解决很多现今面临的复杂难题。
from decoding the human brain,
从对人脑的解析，
to understanding the vast universe out there.
到探索广袤的宇宙。
On your left side, you have a snapshot of a neural network of a mouse --
左边是一张有关老鼠的神经网络图片。
very similar to our own at this particular scale.
这种尺度下看和人类的很像。
And on your right side, you have the Millennium Simulation.
右边的是“千禧模拟”
It was the largest and most realistic simulation of the growth of cosmic structure.
它是最大型且最接近现实的关于宇宙演化的模拟。
It was able to recreate the history of 20 million galaxies
它能再现两千万星系的历史，
in approximately 25 terabytes of output.
并输出成大约有25TB的数据。
And coincidentally or not,
无独有偶，
I just find this particular comparison
当我对比这两张图，
between the smallest scale of knowledge -- the brain --
一个是最小尺度的知识——大脑，
and the largest scale of knowledge -- the universe itself --
一个是最大尺度的知识——宇宙。
to be really quite striking and fascinating.
都如此繁复而美妙。
Because as Bruce Mau once said,
正如 Bruce Mau 所说，
"When everything is connected to everything else,
“当所有事物彼此互相关联，
for better or for worse, everything matters."
无论好坏，所有的事物都变得重要。”
Thank you so much.
谢谢。
(Applause)
（掌声）